ChangSeok Oh

E-mail: changseok@gnome.org Mobile: +1 (404) 740-7896 Blog: http://medium.com/@changseok 251 10th street NW A202 Atlanta, GA 30318, United States

Summary

Open source enthusiast and hacker specializing in web domain and linux-based system. WebKit committer and GNOME foundation member. More than 9 years experience at major players in the relevant industry and academy. Interested in opportunities related with web technology, computer graphics and linux system stack.

Education

O8/2017 - present

Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A.
Ph.D. Student majoring in Computer Science at SSLab

O3/2000 - O6/2008

Ajou University in Suwon, South Korea
B.E. in Digital Media (intensive major course)
B.E. in Information and Computer Engineering (second major)

Research Interests

Web, System, Security, Computer graphics, Open source

Experience

08/2018 - present

Research Assistance at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech

06/2016 - 07/2017

Research associate at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech

As a research scientist, I contributed to research projects in which Georgia Tech partakes for national interests.

1. Building continuous resource monitoring system to detect low-volume DDoS attacks. The low-volume DDoS attack is an attack using small volume of malicious traffics crafted to exploit a flow in systems and causing a target system to exhaust resources without being noticed. In this project, I have built a strategy and a monitoring system to defeat such attacks. The monitoring system is implemented in linux kernel and continuously watches resources such as cpu, memory usage necessary to process each incoming packet. Unlike other solutions (e.g., cgroup), the new system gathers resource information centered on a requested data and measures them even in interrupts.

08/2012 - 03/2016

Software engineer at Collabora Ltd.

Collabora Ltd. is a UK based software consultancy specializing in delivering the benefits of open source to the commercial world. As a software engineer in web domain, I participated in many interesting projects based on WebKit and Chromium/Blink.

1. WebKitClutter port for Apertis

Apertis is an IVI system based on linux, driven by Bosch. It was open-sourced later. For the project, I worked on shifting existing features and APIs to WebKit2 multi-process based architecture. Also, improving performance by using OpenGL and multi-threading architecture were my major contributions. (link, patches)

2. GNOME Web (a.k.a Epiphany) for Raspbian

This project aimed to bring full browser experience to Raspberry Pi users using Raspbian, the default OS for Raspberry Pi and one of Debian variation. At that time, I improved performance for playing html5 video and scrolling. In addition, I developed some new features such as Disk Image Cache and Memory Pressure Handler based on linux cgroup memory resource controller. (link)

3. SDK 2.5, 3.0 and 4.0 for Smart TV Alliance

Smart TV Alliance is a union of TV manufacturers and developers. They provide a SDK including an IDE and an Emulator compliant with each specifications for app developers to test their apps. In this project, I made all webkit changes to meet each requirement of SDK 2.5-4.0.

07/2008 - 08/2012

Assistant Software engineer at SAMSUNG Electronics.

When I worked for SAMSUNG Electronics, I was in Software Platform Team, DMC R&D Center and performed several research projects. Some of them already went in public as products.

1. WebKitEFL port for TIZEN

I contributed to WebGL implementation and hardware acceleration via OpenGL ES. This was an initial effort to add OpenGL ES backend to the WebKit Project.

2. Full browser for SAMSUNG Smart TV 2010

This project brought full browser experience to SAMSUNG Smart TV series released in 2010. My role was to build, integrate and implement UI by using html, css and javascript.

3. Maple, in-house web engine for SAMSUNG connected TVs and all-in-one printers.

Maple was an in-house web engine that adopted the SpiderMonkey as javascript interpreter from the Mozilla Gecko engine. I ported the TraceMonkey, a new javascript engine of Gecko into the project.

07/2007 - 06/2008

Intern at SAMSUNG Software Membership.

Two projects were performed in this period. They were very experimental and related with computer graphics. Also, I developed a 3D train racing game by using DirectX on MS Windows during this period. (video)

Open Source Projects

04/2013 - present

Committer at WebKit

I have contributed WebGL enhancement, hardware acceleration through OpenGL/ES, layout bugfixes, memory pressure handler for linux platform and WebKitGTK+ port features such as JPEG-XR decoder, customizable widgets and threaded compositor enhancement. (patches)

10/2013 - present

Member at GNOME foundation

I am a GNOME foundation member because of my contribution to WebKitGTK+. Also, I've translated GNOME Web (a.k.a Epiphany) to Korean and its help document since 2014. (patches)

01/2015 - present

Contributor at Chromium/Blink

I have been soliciting for committership. I have 30 landed patches so far. One of my contribution is to make chromium/blink support the 'font-size-adjust' css property. (patches)

Presentations

12/07/2014	Web Engines Hackfest 2014 in A Coruña, Spain Raspberry Pi Browser by changseok & kov (slides)
09/29/2014	DEVIEW 2014 in Seoul, South Korea Lessons from developing a web browser for Raspberry Pi (slides, video)
04/25/2014	Jeju University in Jeju, South Korea Introduction to GNOME (slides)
10/27/2013	DevOn 2013 in Seoul, South Korea GNOME & You (slides)

Patents

05/25/2011 Web page management method and apparatus and storage medium thereof

US 20110296323

05/20/2011 | Method of re-searching webpage and apparatus and storage medium therefor

US 20110289110

10/15/2010 Interface method and display device

US 20110093606

10/15/2010 Interface method and display device

US 20110090165

Grants

12/2013 - 11/2014 Open Frontier (₩3,000,000 and ₩300,000 per month)

Languages

English | Proficient

Korean Native

References

Prof. Taesoo Kim

Georgia Institute of Technology Room 3142 Klaus Advanced Computing Building 266 Ferst Drive NW Atlanta, GA 30332-0765 +1-404-385-2934 taesoo@gatech.edu

Prof. Gyuhwan Oh

Ajou University Sanhakgwan 407, 206, World cup-ro, Yeongtong-gu Suwon-si, Gyeonggi-do South Korea +82-031-219-1836 drghoh@ajou.ac.kr

Gustavo Noronha Silva

Web Domain Lead, Principal Software Engineer Collabora Ltd. Kett House, Station Road Cambridge CB1 2JH United Kingdom +44 (0)1223 362967 gustavo.noronha@collabora.com

Prof. Changwoo Min

Virginia Tech Room 455 Durham Hall Blacksburg, VA 24060 +1-540-231-4580 changwoo@vt.edu

Prof. Hyunjoon Shin

Ajou University Sanhakgwan 608, 206, World cup-ro, Yeongtong-gu, Suwon-si, Gyeonggi-do South Korea +82-031-219-1837 joony@ajou.ac.kr

Joone Hur

Senior Software Engineer Intel Open Source Technology Center +1-503-840-9899, +1-503-712-4556 joone.hur@intel.com

Last update : 06/18/2018